What is the difference between a merge and a rebase?

Merge -> Merges changes to a branch into the original branch, essentially combining the edited branch with the original. It also preserves the history of the separate branches.
Rebase -> Moves changes from one branch to another, instead of combining two branches into one. It does not preserve the history of the separate branches and instead creates a linear one, which can reduce clutter.
